# Aleksandra Dacko

I'm a current student in a master's programme in Methodology & Statistics for the Behavioural, Biomedical and Social Sciences at Utrecht University. I got experience in Data Analytics, programming and academic research. My master project is about Hidden Markov Model and Hidden Semi-Markov Model in a multilevel framework. I admire working in a team as much as being independent, taking responsibility for my decisions, and solving problems. All of my technical and soft skills add up to a Data Scientist profile, and that's the job I'm aiming for.



### Contact detalis



ola.dacko.15@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/a-dacko



github.com/a-dacko

### Skills

- R (Programming/Supervised Learning)
- Microsoft Power Query/ Excel
- Python (Scikit, pandas and plotly)
- Version control (GitHub)
- Basic Power BI and Shiny Dashboard
- Jupiter Notebook and R markdown
- Hidden Markov Models
- · Intensive longitudinal data analysis
- Statistical Consultancy
- · Strong critical thinking

# Language

- · Polish (native)
- English (level C1)
- Russian (level A1)
- German (level A1)

### Courses

- Learning Data Analytics Part 1 and 2
- Data Fluency course
- pandas and SQL Essential Training
- · Python for Data Visualization
- · More on my LinkedIn profile!

### Interests



Nolleyball



Data Visualization



Cooking and Baking

# **Volunteering**

#### Academic Volleyball team's coach

Aberystwyth University, UK Jun 2022-Aug 2022

- Organizing activities for up to 40 people during training sessions.
- Coaching team during academic games.
- Teaching volleyball to players from beginner to advanced level.

# **Experience**

#### **Graduate Research Assistant**

Utrecht University, NL

#### Feature Selection for data imputation

Oct 2022-now

Co-leader of a research project on feature selection for data imputation, under a Mice package research group (R package for data imputation). In particular, focused on high-dimensional data.

https://github.com/danadria/feature.selector

#### Data Science courses review

Oct 2022-now

Creating an interactive Shiny Dashboard about data science courses provided by Utrecht University. The product is going to serve as a marketing tool for individuals considering this type of education.

https://github.com/a-dacko/UU-DS-courses

#### Information Criterion, research and R package development Jan 2022-Jun 2022

- Creating and running research simulations on effect size measurements.
- · Contributing to the newest version of the restriktor R package by implementing additional features for users.

https://github.com/a-dacko/restriktor

#### Hidden Markov Models, research and R package development Nov 2021-Jun 2022

- · Contribution to the development of mHMMbayes R package (package allowing to estimate Multilevel Hidden Markov models).
- · Creating visualization functions.
- Running test analysis to investigate the science field usage perspective.

https://github.com/a-dacko/mHMMbayes

#### **Data Analyst Intern**

Verisk Kraków, PL

Jun 2022-Aug 2022

- · Working with insurance data.
- Preparation and automatization of one of the Customer Insights reports:
  - o retrieve data from a database, using SQL,
  - o manipulating and organizing data using the pandas library in Python,
  - o creating data insights summary document.

## **Education**

#### **Utrecht University**

2021-2023

Master | Methodology & Statistics for the Behavioural, Biomedical and Social Sciences

#### Aberystwyth University

2018-2021

Bachelor of Science | Pure Mathematics/Statistics: First Class Honours